不  你想  液态金属终结者
No, see, the liquid-metal terminators were created
是天网系统在未来世界创造的角色
In the future by skynet,
而天网系统是由麦尔斯·戴森开发的
And skynet was developed by miles dyson,
但这样的未来不会存在了
But that future no longer exists
因为戴森已经在终结者2里死了
Due to dyson's death in terminator 2.
好吧  但你这样想
Okay,read only this.
假设所有正义的终结者一开始
Assuming all the good terminators
由天网系统创造时都是邪恶的
Were originally evil terminators created by skynet
是后来经约翰·康纳之手才重新改编了其程序
But then reprogrammed by the future john connor,
那为什么天网系统  如此一个人工智能
Why would skynet, an artificial computer intelligence,
会去创造一个火辣的17岁小矮个机器人杀手?
Bother to create a petite, hot, 17-year-old killer robot?
因为天网系统变态?
Skynet is kinky?
我不知道
I don't know...
人工智能可不会把小屁孩当恋物
Artificial intelligences do not have teen fetishes.
好吧  等等  其实他们是想用它...
All right. Wait! they use it to...
太晚了  我赢了
Too late. I win.
这究竟是什么玩意?
What the hell is that?
我不知道  但如果猫可以唱歌
I don't know, but if cats could sing...
它们也会受不了这个
They'd hate it, too.
好啊  伙计们
Hey, guys!
你们去哪儿?
Hi! where you going?
什么
What?
我们出去寄些信  还有...
We just had to mail some letters and...
顺便把这些鸡肉扔了
Throw away some chicken.
你们肯定猜不到刚才发生了什么
You'll never guess what just happened.
我猜不到
Oh, I give up.
我根本不用猜
I don't guess.
作为一名科学家  我们通过
As a scientist, I reach conclusions
观察和试验来得出结论...
Based on observation and experimentation...
虽然我现在正这么说
Although as I'm saying this,
但我感觉你可能已经使用了
It occurs to me you may have been employing
某种能带修辞的表达装置来使我的回应倍受争议
A rhetorical device rendering my response moot.
那是什么东西?
What was that?
你信不信  他现在开窍了
Believe it or not, personal growth.
是什么事?
What happened?
是这样  记不记得我曾经参加了
All right, remember when I auditioned for that workshop
出租产品展示会的试镜却没通过
Production of rent, but I didn't get it
并且我没想通是什么原因?
And I couldn't figure out why.
通过观察我得出了一点结论
I have a conclusion based on an observation.
不  你没有
No, you don't.
不  他没有
No, he doesn't.
他们选中的那个女孩
Well, the girl they picked to play mimi--
她退出了  然后他们让我替代她
She dropped out, and they asked me to replace her.
恭喜你  这是个契机啊
Congratulations. what a lucky break.
没什么大不了的  就一晚上的亮相
It's not that big a deal, just a one-night showcase,
但他们请了好多剧组人员和经纪人来
But they invite a lot of casting people and agents.
去了才知道啦...
So, you never know.
-我想我知道  -不  你不知道
I think I know. no, you don't.
他不知道
He doesn't.
这周五晚8点  你们想不想来?
It's this friday night at 8:00. you guys want to come?
-不  -不
No. no.
因为...
Because... uh...
周五我们要参加一个
Friday we are attending a symposium
关于分子正负的研讨会
On molecular positronium.
我以为是下周二6点呢
I think that's a week from tuesday,at 6:00.
不  是这个周五
No, it's this friday.
8点
At 8:00.
太遗憾了
Oh, too bad.
好了  我得去排练了
Well, I gotta get to rehearsal.
-再见了  伙计们  -再见
See you guys. see ya.
你刚才对潘妮撒了谎
You just lied to penny.
-是  我撒了谎  -而且你表现得
Yes, I did. and you did it
如此从容  没有呼吸急促
So casually-- no rapid breathing,
也没有冒汗
No increase in perspiration...
所以说?
So?
所以说  你撒谎时缺乏生理反应
So, lack of a physiological response while lying
这是反社会暴力狂的特点
Is characteristic of a violent sociopath.
谢尔顿  你是在担心你的人身安全吗
Sheldon, are you worried about your safety?
不  我想如果你要杀了我
No, I imagine if you were going to kill me,
你早就下手了
You'd have done it a long time ago.
说得非常正确
That's very true.
《生活大爆炸》
第一季  第10集
The.Loobenfeld.Decay
莱纳德
Leonard?
-莱纳德  -干嘛
Leonard? what?
我得找你谈谈
I need to speak to you.
现在是凌晨2点
It's 2:00 in the morning!
很重要的事
It's important.
我严重怀疑
I highly doubt that.
走开
Go away.
你还在外面吗
Are you still out there?
没错
Yes.
干嘛
What?
你说的对  我们还是天亮了再说吧
You're right; it can wait until morning.
什么  什么  什么  什么  什么
What, what, what, what, what?
没事儿
Never mind.
很明显我在你熟睡的时候叫醒了你
I clearly woke you up in the middle of a rem cycle.
你根本就没心情听我说话
You're in no state of mind to talk.
谢尔顿  到底什么事
Sheldon, what is it?
卷入了你对潘妮的欺骗事件我感到很不舒服
I'm uncomfortable having been included in your lie to penny.
那我应该怎么说
What was I supposed to say?
你可以跟她说实话
You could have told her the truth.
那样会伤害她的
That would have hurt her feelings.
这跟伤害她有什么关系?
Is that a relevant factor?
当然有
Yes.
那我想你应该答应她去的
Then I suppose you could've agreed to go.
那我之后该怎么说?
And what would I have said afterwards?
我会这么说
I would suggest something to be a fact of
唱歌对你来说既不是一个合适的职业
Singing is neither an appropriate vocation
也不是合适的副业  如果你不同意
Nor avocation for you, and if you disagree,
我建议你去做一个X光断层扫描
I'd recommend you have a cat scan
看看是不是有肿瘤
To look for a tumor pressing
压迫到了你大脑的认知处理单元
On the cognitive processing centers of your brain.
我可说不出来
I couldn't say that.
我只会说  你真的太棒了
I would have to say, "you were terrific
我好想再听一遍你的歌声
And I can't wait to hear you sing again."
为什么
Why?
这是人们交际的法则
That's the social protocol.
当你朋友对自己很烂的东西引以为傲时
It's what you do when you have a friend
你就应该这么做
Who's proud of something they really suck at.
我以前不知道
I was not aware of that.
那你现在知道了
Well, now you are. oh.
好吧  莱纳德
All right. leonard?
怎么
Yes?
记得我们以前玩国际象棋吗
When we played chess earlier,
你真的太棒了  我真想能有机会再跟你切磋
You were terrific, and I can't wait to play you again.
晚安
Good night.
莱纳德
Leonard?
如果我真是反社会暴力狂
This would be so much easier
那就好办多了
If I were a violent sociopath.
莱纳德  莱纳德
Leonard? leonard?
怎么了
What?
我刚才分析了下我们的谎话  我在想
I was analyzing our lie, and I believe we're in danger
潘妮要是看穿了我们的骗局  我们就危险了
Of penny seeing through the ruse.
怎么会
How?
很简单  如果她登陆
Simple, If she were to log onto
Www.socalphysixsgroup.org /Activities/Other(一学术网站)
Www.socalphysixsgroup.org /activities/other,
点击"最近活动"  往下滚找到"研讨会"
Click on "upcoming events," scroll down to "seminars,"
下载日程安排
Download the pdf schedule,
然后查找分子正负的研讨会
And look for the seminar on molecular positronium,
那可好了
Well than...
我们就要火烧屁股了
Our pants are metaphorically on fire.
好吧  先生  我今天不会让火烧到我屁股的
Well, sir, my trousers will not be igniting today.
潘妮
Penny?
早上好
Good morning.
你知不知道现在几点?
Do you have any idea what time it is?
我当然知道
Of course I do.
我的手表连接着科罗拉多州的
My watch is linked to the atomic clock
波尔得的原子钟
In boulder, colorado.
精确到0.1秒
It's accurate to one-tenth of a second.
但我在这说话的同时  再一次
But as I'm saying this, it occurs to me
我感觉你的问题可能是带修辞性的
That, once again, your question may have been rhetorical.
你要干什么
What do you want?
还记得莱纳德怎么跟你说
Remember how leonard told you
为什么我们不能去看你表演吗
We couldn't come to your performance
因为我们要参加研讨会
Because we were attending a symposium
关于分子正负的
On molecular positronium?
我记得有个研讨会
I remember "symposium."
是的  那是他骗你的
Yes. well... he lied.
等等
Wait.
什么
What?
他跟你撒谎了
He lied
我对此感到很忐忑不安
And I'm feeling very uncomfortable about it.
知道我是什么感觉吗
Well, imagine how I'm feeling.
饿?
Hungry?
累?
Tired?
对不起  这真的不是我的强项
I'm sorry, this really isn't my strong suit.
你告诉他我骗她?
You told her I lied?
你为什么要告诉她我骗她?
Why would you tell her I lied?
为了帮你
To help you.
不好意思  我没看到哪里有帮助
I'm sorry, I'm not seeing the help.
她最终肯定会看穿你的谎言
She was going to see through your lie eventually,
所以  为了保护我  我告诉她你撒了谎
So I told her that you were lying to protect me.
我有种不好的感觉
Ohh... I'm getting a bad feeling.
饿了?
Hunger?
消化不良?
Indigestion?
对不起  我真的不擅长这个
I'm sorry, I'm really not very good at this.
总之
Anyway,
潘妮现在已经相信
Penny now believes that, on friday night,
周五的晚上我们要去参加
We're going to participate
我表弟里奥珀德的戒毒调停会
In my cousin leopold's drug intervention.
你的表弟里奥珀德
Your cousin leopold.
大部分人叫他里奥  但你叫他里他也会答应
Who most people call leo, but he also answers to lee.
记住这点  这很关键
Remember that. it's important.
有什么好关键的?
What's important?
细节  莱纳德
Details, leonard-- the success
骗人的成功或失败
Or failure of our deceitful enterprise
就是取决于细节
Turns on details.
-你真有个表弟叫里奥珀德?  -没有
Do you have a cousin leopold? no.
他是我捏造的
I made him up.
我觉得你应该叫他里
I think you'd call him lee.
我不明白了
I don't get it.
我已经跟她撒过一次谎了
I already told her a lie.
为什么要再撒一个不同的谎?
Why replace it with a different lie?
首先  你的谎话很可笑且容易被识破
Well, first of all, your lie was laughably transparent,
而我的却十分缜密且难以识破
Where mine is exquisitely convoluted.
在你睡觉的时候
While you were sleeping,
我组建了一个"非不可解释"网站
I was weaving an un-unravelable web.
非不可解释?
Un-unravelable?
是的
Yes.
如果她在Google里搜索"里奥珀德·休斯顿"
If she googles "leopold houston,"
她会找到一个Facebook(美国交友网站)页面
She'll find a facebook page,
一个在线博客  里面有描述他吸毒走向堕落的过程
An online blog depicting his descent into drug use
而且在Eharmony.com(美国婚介网站)有个绝望但仍有希望的名单
And a desperate yet hopeful listing on eharmony.com.
好吧  但是为什么
Okay, why would I go
我要去参加你表弟的戒毒调停会
To a drug intervention for your cousin?
因为那在长滩  而我又不会开车
Ah! because it's in long beach, and I don't drive.
我们要去长滩?
We're going to long beach?
不  当然不  根本就没有表弟里奥
No, of course not. there's no cousin leo.
也没有调停会
There's no intervention.
动动脑子  莱纳德
Focus, leonard.
不会吧
Aw, come on.
我们只需要在周五晚上离开家
We just leave the house on friday night and we return
然后等到凌晨再回来
In the wee hours, emotionally wrung out,
带着一幅坚信里奥回戒毒所后能改邪归正的表情
From the work of convincing leo to go back into rehab.
他还要回戒毒所?
He goes back into rehab?
没错  并且  要是潘妮再邀请我们听她唱歌
Yes, but, he can relapse if penny
他随时可以毒瘾发作的
Ever invites us to hear her sing again.
你毕竟还是告诉她我撒谎了
You still told her I lied.
但初衷很高尚的  你是为了帮助我
For a noble purpose-- to spare me
避免让人知道我有个吸毒的弟弟
The social embarrassment
这一让人尴尬的事情
Of having a drug-addled first cousin--
我假设这是很尴尬  对吗
Which I'm assuming is embarrassing, yes?
我怎么可能记住这么多乱七八糟的
How am I supposed to remember all of this?
最精彩的部分到了  你根本不用去记
Oh, that's the best part. you don't have to.
我对潘妮说如果你发现
See, I told penny that you would be embarrassed
她知道你骗她的话  你会很尴尬
If you knew that she found out that you had lied,
所以  她同意装作像上个谎话
So she's agreed to operate
还没被拆穿一样  装作什么都不知道
As if the original lie is still in force.
所以她以为我是撒谎
So she's expecting me to lie about going
说去帕萨迪纳市开研讨会
To a symposium in pasadena,
而实际上  我们假装正要去
When, in actuality, we're pretending
长滩参加你弟弟的戒毒调停会
To go to a drug intervention in long beach.
非不可解释
Un-unravelable.
潘妮
Oh, hey, penny.
你看看你  都整装待发准备好演出了
Wow, look at you, all ready for your showcase.
-你看上去真漂亮  -谢谢
You look great. thanks.
我只是想过来看看并且祝你们好运
I just wanted to come by and wish you guys luck
关于你们的...研讨会
With your... symposium.
谢谢你
Well, thank you.
我必须要跟你说  很多人都会
You know, I got to tell you, a lot of friends
让他们的朋友孤零零一个人
Would let their friend go alone,
但你不是这样的人
But that's not who you are.
你是那种总陪在朋友身边的人
You are the kind of guy who stands by a friend
即使当他有个...研讨会要去参加
When... when he has a symposium to go to.
我不知道怎么说
I don't know what to say.
没事的  莱纳德
It's okay, leonard.
哦  好的  不错
Oh, okay, all right, good.
伙计  大家一起来抱抱
Oh, boy, group hug. uh-uh.
好吧
Okay.
怎么了?
So, what's up?
潘妮正要去一个
Well, penny is on her way to perform
出租用品展示会进行表演
In a one-night showcase production of rent,
而我们不能去了  因为我们要去参加
Which we are unable to attend, because we're going
由伊米尔·法尔曼法尔米安博士主讲的
To a symposium on molecular positronium
关于分子正负的研讨会
Given by dr. emil farmanfarmian.
等等  法尔曼法尔米安要来
Wait a minute-- farmanfarmian is speaking
而你们竟然霸占这个研讨会?
And you're bogarting the symposium?
霍华德  对不...我们...
Howard, I'm sorr... we-we...
不  不  你们保密到连夸克都透不过
No, no, you're quark-blocking us.
我不知道怎么说
I don't know what to say.
-霍华德  听着...  -不  没关系
Howard, listen... no, it's okay.
那是你的命根子
It's your millennium falcon.
你可以跟楚巴卡(体型高大、身披毛发的战士)得到任何你们想要的
You and chewbacca do whatever you want to do.
我跟莱娅公主(星战人物)
Me and princess leia here
会找点别的事来度过今晚
Will find some other way to spend the evening.
霍华德  等等
Howard, wait. wai...
谢尔顿  我觉得我们得告诉他们
Sheldon, I think we should tell them.
好吧  当然可以
Okay, sure.
我觉得没有任何问题
I don't see a problem with that.
根本就没有什么研讨会
There's no symposium.
莱纳德跟我撒了谎  是不是  莱纳德?
Leonard lied to me. isn't that right, leonard?
我不知道怎么说
I don't know what to say!
没关系  我来说
It's okay; I do.
莱纳德其实在帮谢尔顿解决家庭危机
Look, leonard is helping sheldon through a family crisis.
他编了整个什么研讨会的故事
He made up the whole story about the symposium
什么法尔曼...法尔米安...博士
With dr. farman... farmian...
你真强
Good for you.
因为他不想让谢尔顿尴尬
...because he didn't want sheldon to be embarrassed.
其实这根本没什么可尴尬的  知道吗
And there is nothing to be embarrassed about, okay?
在美国谁家都会有个亲戚
Every family in america has a relative
干点不大光彩的事情
Holed up in a garage somewhere huffing paint thinner.
不  我也糊涂了
No, I'm lost, too.
我觉得她跳过了一步
I think she skipped a step.
不是  你们听我说
No, look.
谢尔顿的表弟里奥逃离了戒毒所
Sheldon's cousin leo escaped rehab,
他现在躲在长滩的一家汽车旅馆
And he's in a motel 8 in long beach.
他们全家出动参加调停会
The whole family's going out for an intervention.
莱纳德要开车送谢尔顿去
Leonard is driving sheldon down there
帮他表弟渡过难关  因为他真的是个好人哦
To help him through this, because he's such a good man.
又抱我一次?  谢谢
Oh, another hug? thank you.
好了  朋友们  祝你们好运
All right, you guys, good luck.
谢谢  潘妮
Thanks, penny.
祝你演出成功
Oh-- break a leg.
演出成功
Break a leg.
开车去长滩
So, road trip to long beach.
不  我们不去长滩
No. we're not going to long beach.
为什么
Why not?
因为谢尔顿根本就没有一个
Because sheldon doesn't have
吸毒的叫里奥珀德的表弟
A drug-addicted cousin leopold.
太遗憾了
Oh, too bad.
我一直都想去长滩
I've always wanted to go to long beach.
的确是个不错的地方
It's a very nice community.
玛丽女王号就停靠在那里
The queen mary is docked there.
它曾是世上最大的远洋客轮
Once the largest ocean liner in the world,
现在成了一家酒店和餐厅
It's now a hotel and restaurant,
为顾客提供极其扣人心弦的
Where they host a surprisingly gripping
离奇谋杀主题晚宴
Murder mystery dinner.
听起来挺有趣  我要去
Sounds fun. I'm game.
出发!
Shotgun!
别  别  别
No, no, no.
莱纳德要坐前排  否则他会恶心呕吐
Leonard gets nauseous unless he sits in front,
不过即便这样  也很难保证
And even then, it's iffy.
等等  我们...真要去长滩啊?!
Wait, are we... really going to long beach?!
莱纳德
Leonard?
莱纳德  莱纳德
Leonard? leonard?
别再想了  谢尔顿
Let it go, sheldon.
不管你觉得说不说得通
The murderer was the first mate
谋杀犯就是第一个同事
Whether it makes sense to you or not.
不是  我才不关心那个呢
No, that's the least of our worries.
我一直在做一些关于吸毒方面的研究...
I've been doing some research on addiction--
既有生物化学方面的也有行为方面的...
Both the biochemical and behavioral aspects--
我觉得我们现在这个
And I think there's a problem
版本的谎话有个问题
With the current version of our lie.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
无所谓了  她相信了  都结束了
It's fine-- she bought it; it's over.
可惜的是  并没有
Sadly, it's not.
对抗毒品不是一朝一夕的事
Substance abuse is a lifelong struggle,
抛开这点  我意识到我所描述的这个里奥
But beyond that, I have realized that the leo I described
根本就不会同意到戒毒所接受治疗
Would not have agreed to go to rehab.
为什么
Why not?
因为里奥是中间儿
Because leo's a middle child.
中间儿综合症是指排行老二或者排在中间的孩子，
由于没有老大或最小的孩子那么“受关注”，因此产生的一些心理问题
根本就没里奥这个人!
There is no leo!
你怎么就能说这些?
How can you say that?
你没读过他的简历  是吗
You didn't read the bio, did you?
他不仅是个中间儿
He's not just a middle child,
他更是个典型的中间儿...
He is the quintessential middle child--
附:他出自破碎家庭
From a broken home, to boot.
从心理学上讲  即使会导致自我毁灭
Psychologically speaking, the attention he gets by rebelling,
对他来说  通过反抗所获得的关注度
Even to the point of self-destruction,
在情感上的价值要远远超过康复治疗所带来的效果
Is more emotionally valuable than the help he would get at rehab.
我倒有个主意
I've got a solution.
太好了  什么
Great. what is it?
出  去!
Get out!
好吧
Fine.
我一直犹豫要不要说
I've hesitated to point this out,
但我必须提醒你的是
But I must now remind you that we
我们目前的窘境完全是因为你先前
Are in our current predicament because of your initial
理由相当不充分的欺骗行为造成的
And totally inadequate deceit.
我只是想替你收拾残局而已
I'm just trying to clean up after your mess.
我们明早再说
We'll talk in the morning.
早
Morning.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是谢尔顿的表弟里奥
I am sheldon's cousin leo.
谢尔顿根本没有一个叫里奥的表弟
Sheldon does not have a cousin leo.
恰恰相反
Au contraire.
我今年26岁
I'm 26 years old.
我的祖籍是...德克萨斯州的登顿市
I'm originally from... denton, texas,
但我是个海军顽童  所以我从小
But I was a navy brat, so I was
是在世界各地的军事基地长大的
Brought up on a variety of military bases around the world.
因此  我总感觉跟群体格格不入...
As a result, I've often felt like an outsider--
从没真正融入过
Never really fitting in,
这也很可能是我滥用毒品的原因
Which is probably the reason for my substance abuse problem.
打扰一下  我们刚才还练习过一遍
Excuse me, we just went over this.
作为一个典型的中间儿  你的赌瘾
As the quintessential middle child, your addiction
根植于你未被满足的对关注度的需求当中
Is rooted in your unmet need for attention.
谢尔顿  我们不是真的要用通俗心理学吧?
Oh, sheldon, are we really going to go with pop psychology?
请注意  这些都是以有力的研究为根据的
For your information, this is all based on solid research.
完全依照我写给你的性格档案就行了
Just stick with the character profile I wrote for you.
-谢尔顿?  -不好意思
Sheldon? I'm sorry.
莱纳德  这位是托比·鲁本菲尔德
Leonard, this is toby loobenfeld.
他是粒子物理实验室的
He's a research assistant
一名研究助理
In the particle physics lab,
不过他同时在麻省理工辅修戏剧
But he also minored in theater at mit.
事实上  说双学位更准确些
It was more of a double major, actually.
戏剧和物理
Theater and physics.
可以猜一下哪门是我中产阶级的父母
You can guess which one my bourgeois parents
逼我学的
Pushed me toward.
行了  我知道了
Yeah, I got it.
谢尔顿...你这是为什么
Sheldon... why?
你想啊  鉴于里奥不会去接受康复治疗
You see, while leo would not have gone into rehab,
那我们把他从汽车旅馆劝回家
It is completely plauible that we would have talked him
就是完全可以解释通的了
Into leaving the motel and coming home with us.
谢尔顿  这样设计
Oh... sheldon, how about this
我的动机如何...我14岁那年
As my motivation-- when I was 14 years old,
在菲律宾被一个先天脚畸形的海军教士虐待
I was abused in the philippines by a clubfooted navy chaplain.
不行  就设计成一个中间儿
No. we're going with middle child
具有血液中复合胺含量不足的遗传体质倾向
And a genetic predisposition to inadequate serotonin production.
亏你想得出来  遗传体质你要我怎么扮?
Swell. how do I play genetic predisposition?
当然是如字面意思所示
Subtextually, of course.
尽情享受就好了
Just have fun with it.
早  潘妮
Morning, penny.
家庭会议开得怎么样?
Hi. how did the intervention go?
很不幸  我们没能说服他去戒毒所接受治疗
Unfortunately, we weren't able to convince him to go to rehab.
基于你昨天跟我说的那些  我一点都不惊讶
Oh. well, based on what you told me, I am not surprised.
但我们说服他搬出汽车旅馆了
But we did convince him to leave the motel.
进来认识一下
Come say hello.
里奥  这位是潘妮
Leo. this is penny,
我们的朋友和邻居
Our friend and neighbor.
你好  里奥
Hi, leo.
你现在感觉如何
How are you feeling?
潘妮  问你个问题
Let me ask you something, penny.
你有过吐得浑身都是  然后一觉醒来
Have you ever woken up in a fleabag motel
发现自己身在一个破烂的汽车旅馆
Covered in your own vomit,
身边还躺着个人妖妓女的经历吗
Next to a transsexual prostitute?
没有
No.
那就别问我感觉如何
Then don't ask me how I'm feeling.
这位就是里奥
Well, that's leo.
跟我说说你昨晚的演出吧
Why don't you tell me about your showcase last night.
还好啦  我觉得
Oh. it was okay, I guess.
场面不算太热烈
It wasn't a big turnout,
但他俩好像都很喜欢我的表演
But they both really seemed to like it.
就俩人?
There were only two people there?
坚持到最后的  是的
By the end, yeah.
你个该死的哈里根教士!
Damn you, chaplain harrigan!
你...你说什么
I'm... I'm sorry?
那是在菲律宾的时候
The philippines.
1992年
1992.
在苏比克湾海军基地
The subic bay naval station.
美国位于菲律宾吕宋岛的海军维修基地
一个年轻的男孩即将步入成年
A young boy on the cusp of manhood.
他的同伴只剩下
His only companions,
杂种狗和疟疾蚊子
Mongrel dogs and malarial mosquitoes.
绝望交织着孤独
Desperate and alone,
他遇见这个许诺将他引荐给
He reached out to a man who promised to introduce him
仁爱上帝的男人
To a merciful, loving god,
但恰恰相反  却将他引荐给了
But who instead introduced him
一个大醉松子酒  舌头卷进喉咙的小青年
To a gin-pickled tongue shoved down his adolescent throat.
除了用酗酒  吸毒
What choice did he have but to drink,
来宣泄痛苦  他还有什么选择呢?
Shoot and snort his pain away?
别忘了是他的遗传体质引发的吸毒成瘾
Don't forget his genetic predisposition towards addiction.
-那从未被证实  -有过很多研究
That's never been proven. there have been studies.
但不是双盲试验啊
Not double-blind studies.
怎么可能实施双盲试验?
How could there be a double-blind study?
谁来做对照组?
Who would be the control group?
正如你看到的  戒毒是件很丑陋的事情
As you can see, detoxing can get pretty ugly.
我们给他们点空间
Let's give them some privacy.
好
Yeah.
想来我家坐坐  喝杯咖啡吗
Hey, do you want to come over to my place, have coffee?
不错啊
Oh, sounds good.
我有我昨晚唱歌的录像
I have a video of me singing last night.
想看吗
Do you want to see it?
为什么不呢?
Gee, why wouldn't i?
这比你亲自去看演出都要精彩
This is even better than you coming to the showcase,
因为我要看着你看着我唱歌
Because now I get to watch you watch me.
是啊...
Yeah...
事情的进展真搞笑
Funny how things work out.
...可是他喜欢那些同伴
...but he loved the companionship
还有他的父亲无法给予他的智慧
And the wisdom that his own father failed to provide.
你父母做了正确的决定
Your parents made the right decision.
我没法这样工作
I cannot work like this.
这种感觉太棒了
This is amazing.
坐在沙发上跟一个女人一起看电视
Just sitting on a couch watching tv with a woman.
不酗酒  不磕药
Not being drunk or, or high
也不用担心你是个人妖
Or wondering if you're a dude down there.
里奥  你真的是个很可爱也很有趣的男生
Leo, you are a very sweet, really funny guy.
你一定会没事的
You're going to do okay.
潘妮  每天都能有这么一次就够了
One day at a time, penny.
每天都能有这么一次就够了
One day at a time.
他还要在这待多久?
How long is he going to stay here?
莱纳德  他是个无家可归的吸毒者
He's a homeless drug addict, leonard.
他能去哪?
Where is he going to go?
天啊  你真得好好学学怎么撒谎了
Boy, you have a lot to learn about lying.